One
Uno
Two
Dos
Three
Tres
What's up pumpers?
¿Qué onda pumpers?
OscarJark speaking
Habla OscarJark
And this is the continuation
Y esta es la continuación
of "the history of Pump" video
del video de la historia de la pump
If you haven't see it already here it is
Si no lo han visto aquó lo dejo
so you don't lose the sequence
para que no pierdan la secuencia
In case you remember it we finished
Y si lo recuerdan pues nos quedamos
in the OBG.
en la OBG
Well, after the OBG in September 2000
Bueno, después de ella en Septiembre del 2000
The OBG season evolution
sale en Corea la Pump it up
was released in korea
"The OBG season evolution"
Which it was sopposed to be called
La cual originalmente se llamaría
"Summer edition"
summer edition
But due to some delays
Pero pues, debido a retrasos
the name was changed
le cambiaron el nombre
because it was't even summer anymore
porque ya ni siquiera iba a ser verano
It was almost the same interface as the OBG
Era casi la misma interfaz de la OBG
In this version 14 songs and 1 remix were added
en esta se agregaron 14 canciones y un remix
The cool thing was that every chart had a crazy
lo cool es que todas contaban con un crazy
Here emerged valuble songs such as
de aquí surgieron joyas como:
Solitary, Run to you, Mr. Larpus
Solitary, Run to you, Mr. Larpus
which was the hardest song
que fue la canción con mayor dificultad
due to the inclusion of sequences
debido a que ya incluía secuencias
of stairs, spins and twists
tipo escalera, vueltas y cambios
new for the time
novedosos para la época.
On December 2000
En diciembre del 2000 sale a la luz
the PIU perfect collection was released
la PIU perfect collection
At this point the audio
Llegados a éste punto la calidad de
quality has improved greatly
los audios ya ha mejorado demasiado
compared to the previous releases
en comparación a las entregas anteriores
In addition to the previous tracks
Ésta versión además de contener las canciones
from older CD's
de los discos anteriores
It gave us
nos ofreció la canción
the most emblematic and known
más emblematica y conocida
song that is popular among no-pumpers
por la gente que no juega Pump
I'm talking about Beethoven virus or
me refiero a Beethoven virus o
"Beethoven virus" as we call it here
"Beethoven virus" como le decimos por aquí
Banya and Taiji Boys were the most
Banya y los Taiji Boys fueron los artistas
popular bands
más sobresalientes
And the award for the most outstanding songs
y el premio para las canciones más sobresalientes
was for Hayuga, I will accept you, Rolling christmas,
fue para Hayuga, I will accept you, Rolling christmas,
space fantasy, unforgettable memories and slam
space fantasy, unforgettable memories y slam
the last 2 were the hardest
siendo estas 2 últimas las más difíciles.
from the recently added
de las recién agregadas.
Mmm, not everything was as sweet as honey
Mmm, no todo fue miel sobre hojuelas
because the display was unintuitive
porque la navegación era poco intuitiva
and not easy for occidental people
y amigable para los occidentales
because everything was in korean.
pues todo estaba en coreano.
In the CD's the songs are numbered
En los discos las canciones van enumeradas
release date wise, for instance
de acuerdo  a la máquina en la que salieron, por ejemplo
the first songs were from 101 and onwards
las primeras van del 101 en adelante
in the fifth which was the "Perfect collection"
en la quinta que era la Perfect collection
they were from 501 onwards
iban del 501 en adelante
The sequence was broken when
La secuencia se vió rota cuando
the rights were granted to F2 systems
le cedieron los derechos a F2 systems
to create the "Extra"
para que hiciera la Extra
they were the creators of "Technomotion"
ellos fueron los creadores de la Technomotion
in which you could plat using 4 arrows
Donde podías jugar con 4 flechas
DDr style
tipo DDR
5 Pump style
5 tipo pump
or 8 Technomotion stlyle.
u 8 tipo Technomotion.
They used songs of which
Ellos utilizaron canciones
they already had the rights
que ya tenía licenciadas
and created Holiday and Can can
Y crearon Holiday y Can can
along with Trash man were
que junto con Trash man fueron
the 3 hadest songs in this version
las 3 canciones más difíciles de la versión
another remarkable tracks from here
Otros tema memorables de aquí
were Starian, Chicken wing
fueron Starian, Chicken wing
FAEP 1 and Monkey magic
FAEP 1 y Monkey magic
A very important improvement the game
Un cambio importantísimos para la jugabilidad
was born here
nació aquí
I'm talking about the long-notes or holds
Me refiero a las long-notes o sostenidos
that were introduced here
que fueron introducidos aquí
as well as the possibility
junto con el rush y la posibilidad
of changing to any level during the same credit
de jugar cualquier nivel en el mismo crédito
before if you started in hard mode
pues antes si empezabas en Hard
every single song had to be of that category
todas tenian que ser en Hard.
Now you were able to change levels now
Ahora ya podías cambiar de niveles
even to doubles.
incluso a dobles.
Crazy mode was called "Extra expert"
El crazy era llamado extra-experto
and they  finally create double charts
y por fin se hicieron pasos en doble
with a higher difficulty
con una mayor dificultad
called doble extra experto
llamados double extra experto
However, either the stepmakers
Sin embargo, o los stepmakers
weren't experienced enough
no tenían mucha experiencia
to create worthy doubles
para hacer dobles rescatables
or they were auto-generated because
o fueron autogenerados porque
the steps were from one side to another
solo te pasaban de un lado a a otro
and they looked like their crazy version
y parecian calcas de la versión en crazy
Holiday was the most valuable
la más rescatable era Holiday
The CD, had several bugs
El disco tenía varios bugs o errores
however, a strong point to the Extra
pero un punto a favor de la Extra
was the number of possible skins
fue la gran cantidad de skins posibles
from little shits, UFOs
desde caquitas, ovnis
even snow-men.
incluso muñecos de nieve.
This version was released in Korea
Ésta versión estuvo de venta en Corea
even though It did
Sin embargo sí se llegó a popularizar
get popular in this continent
de éste lado del charco
For the Pump it up the Premiere
para la Pump it up the Premiere
that was commercialized world wide in 2001
que ya vendía internacionalmente en 2001
some titles and song
se tuvieron que cambiar
names were modified
algunos titles y nombres de canciones
So they were in English and not in Korean
para que estuvieran en inglés y no en coreano.
Version for the US and Brazil
Se creó una versión para Estados Unidos
were created, however, the difficulty
y una para Brasil pero con dificultades
was too easy
super fáciles
that only take on me shone
solo sobresalió Take on me
Little time later " The Prex" came out
Y poco después sale la Prex de
from the union of the Premiere an the Extra
la unión de la Premiere y la Extra
using the same environment from " the Premiere"
con la misma interfaz de la Premiere
We still have a long way
Aún nos queda un largo camino que
to go in the
recorrer en los videos
PIU history videos
de la historia de la pump
That's it for this video
Eso es todo por éste vídeo
See ya!.
See ya!.